<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hugo Toscano</title>
    <link>https://toscano84.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hugo Toscano</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toscano84.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Clustering the Pharmaceutical Industry Stocks</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2019/03/clustering-the-pharmaceutical-industry-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2019/03/clustering-the-pharmaceutical-industry-stocks/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will use two of the most popular clustering methods, hierarchical clustering and k-means clustering, to analyse a data frame related to the financial variables of some pharmaceutical companies. Clustering is an unsupervised learning technique where we segment the data and identify meaningful groups that have similar characteristics. In our case, the goal will be to find these groups within the pharmaceutical companies data. Like we did in the previous posts we will start by loading the required packages to our analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Mining Crime and Punishment &amp; Anna Karenina: A Tidytext Approach</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/12/text-mining-crime-and-punishment-and-anna-karenina-a-tidytext-approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/12/text-mining-crime-and-punishment-and-anna-karenina-a-tidytext-approach/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to a new exciting post! Today I have decided to bring you text mining applied to two of my favorite novels: Crime and Punishment by Dostoyevsky and Anna Karenina by Tolstoy. We will use mainly the incredible tidytext package developed by Julia Silge and David Robinson. You can read more about this package in the book of the same authors Text Mining with R: A Tidytext Approach.
Let us start the analysis of “Crime and Punishment” and “Anna Karenina” by loading the required packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Model to Predict if a Bank Customer accepts Personal Loans</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/11/creating-a-model-to-increase-the-personal-loans-in-banks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/11/creating-a-model-to-increase-the-personal-loans-in-banks/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we will fit a multiple logistic regression model to predict the probability of a bank customer accepting a personal loan based on multiple variables to be described later. Logistic regression is a supervised learning algorithm were the independent variable has a qualitative nature. In this case, corresponding to the acceptance or rejection of a personal loan. This tutorial will build multiple logistic regression models and assess them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>German Elections in the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/11/german-elections-in-the-21st-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/11/german-elections-in-the-21st-century/</guid>
      <description>In this blogpost, we will come back to the subject of the German Elections. We will try to show, mostly visually, the changes in election results during the 21st century. Thus, we will use data from the elections in 2002 to the last ones in 2017. The main focus will be mapping the results of the parties represented in the current Bundestag (German Parliament) during this time span. Let’s start our coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting Airfares on New Routes a Supervised Learning Approach With Multiple Linear Regression</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/10/predicting-airfares-on-new-routes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/10/predicting-airfares-on-new-routes/</guid>
      <description>This post will talk about multiple linear regression in the context of machine learning. Linear regression is one of the simplest and most used approaches for supervised learning. This tutorial will try to help you in how to use the linear regression algorithm. I am also new to the machine learning approach, but I’m very interested in this area given the predictive ability that you can gain from this. Let’s hope I can help you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hints to deal with Missing Values in R</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/10/hints-to-deal-with-missing-values-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/10/hints-to-deal-with-missing-values-in-r/</guid>
      <description>In R missing values are usually, but not always, represented by letters NA. How to deal with missing values is very important in the data analytics world. Missing data can be sometimes tricky while analyzing a data frame, since it should be handled correctly for our statistical analysis. Before diving into more complex details about missing data, the first question that should be asked in any exploratory data analysis is: Do I have missing values in my database?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combine Data frames in R</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/09/combine-data-frames-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/09/combine-data-frames-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, before we start to explore our data, we need to put them together. For instance, we might have them stored in different data frames and we have to join variables from two or more data frames in one. This post will talk about the different functions we can use to achieve that goal. We will be using the dplyr package to combine different data frames.
Firstly, we will show examples related to what is called mutating joins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Leaflet approach to Coffee Chains: Starbucks versus Dunkin&#39; Donuts</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/08/a-leaflet-approach-to-coffee-chains-starbucks-versus-dunkin-donuts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/08/a-leaflet-approach-to-coffee-chains-starbucks-versus-dunkin-donuts/</guid>
      <description>This post talks about making interactive visualizations in R with leaflet(). In this example, I’ll map the USA locations of two of the biggest coffee chains, Starbucks and Dunkin’ Donuts. This package allows us to map data and play interactively with it. For instance, we can zoom in or zoom out to augment or diminish map details, respectively. We can add markers that signal the position of our data in the map and move the mouse cursor over to get information about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuition costs and gdp per capita: A linear regression analysis</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/linear-regression-in-r-a-simple-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/linear-regression-in-r-a-simple-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This post will explore with R one of the simplest approaches to predict a response of a quantitative nature. This approach is called Linear Regression.
I will use a simple Linear Regression to study whether there is any relationship between the gross domestic product (gdp) per capita of each state in the USA and its tuition costs. Therefore, our predictor will be the gdp per capita per state and our response will be the tuition costs per state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to analyse the German Federal Election</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/using-r-to-analyse-the-german-federal-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/using-r-to-analyse-the-german-federal-election/</guid>
      <description>As the title of this post implies we will analyze, using the statistical programming language R, the German Federal Election which took place on 24 September of 2017. It will not be an exhaustive analysis of the results. I’m only interested in visualizing the share of the vote that each party represented in the Parliament (i.e. Bundestag) received in each one of the 16 States of Germany.
In order to make this visualization possible in R, loading the respective packages is the first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog!
I’m Hugo! My background is in Psychology, more specifically, in the area of face perception. Always eager to learn and after falling in love with R, I will blog mostly about data related topics (e.g. importing, wrangling, visualization, statistics). Maybe some Machine Learning, I’m still exploring it.
My goal is to try to help you improve your R skills, by sharing what I am currently learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog!
I&amp;rsquo;m Hugo! My background is in Psychology, more specifically, in the area of face perception. Always eager to learn and after falling in love with R, I will blog mostly about data related topics (e.g. importing, wrangling, visualization, statistics). Maybe some Machine Learning, I&amp;rsquo;m still exploring it.
My goal is to try to help you improve your R skills, by sharing what I am currently learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>