<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Hugo Toscano</title>
    <link>https://toscano84.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Hugo Toscano</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://toscano84.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tuition costs and gdp per capita: A linear regression analysis</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/linear-regression-in-r-a-simple-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/linear-regression-in-r-a-simple-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This post will explore with R one of the simplest approaches to predict a response of a quantitative nature. This approach is called Linear Regression.
I will use a simple Linear Regression to study whether there is any relationship between the gross domestic product (gdp) per capita of each state in the USA and its tuition costs. Therefore, our predictor will be the gdp per capita per state and our response will be the tuition costs per state.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using R to analyse the German Federal Election</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/using-r-to-analyse-the-german-federal-election/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/using-r-to-analyse-the-german-federal-election/</guid>
      <description>As the title of this post implies we will analyze, using the statistical programming language R, the German Federal Election which took place on 24 September of 2017. It will not be an exhaustive analysis of the results. I’m only interested in visualizing the share of the vote that each party represented in the Parliament (i.e. Bundestag) received in each one of the 16 States of Germany.
In order to make this visualization possible in R, loading the respective packages is the first step.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toscano84.github.io/2018/07/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog!
I&amp;rsquo;m Hugo! My background is in Psychology, more specifically, in the area of face perception. Always eager to learn and after falling in love with R, I will blog mostly about data related topics (e.g. importing, wrangling, visualization, statistics). Not yet Machine Learning, still exploring it.
My goal is to try to help you improve your R skills, by sharing what I am currently learning.
Other interests I also have, non-data related, are history, tv shows and literature, which I can eventually blog about.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>